《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break
我要总统特赦放我哥哥和我
I want a presidential pardon for me and my brother.
告诉我怎么回事
You tell me what's going on...
我能帮你
I can take care of you.
只要你能告诉我马宏对你说的一切
All I need you to do is tell me exactly what agent Mahone told you.
我得做事 必须去做
I have a job to do, which I've been made to do.
接电话啊   别动 别动
Get off the phone. Wait.Wait.
待那别动
Stay right where you are.
嘿!
Hey!
要是我能帮你找到那5百万呢?
What if I know where you can get at $5 million?
在哪?
Where is it?
我可以带你去
I could take you there,
只要你不把我送回美国监狱
if you didn't have to take me back to the states and turn me back in.
三张票 同一个舱 单程
Free tickets,one cabin,one-way.
很好
Nice
先生 再过几分钟
Sir,in just a few minutes
总统就会宣布对斯科菲尔德和布伦斯的特赦
the president's going to announce a pardon for Burrows and Scofield.
很遗憾的告诉你们
I regret to inform you,
我将不再担任美利坚和众国的总统
I am stepping down as president of the united states.
现在我们能做的就只有
There's only one thing we can do.
消失在这个世界上了
We gotta disappear.
永远地消失
Forever.
你的包
aqui es to maleta,senor Stammel.
谢谢
Gracias.
好重啊 是什么东西?
It's very heavy. What have you got in there?
一点都不关你事 多事的伙计
About 75 pounds of none of your business,Pedro.
亏我帮了你呢
For your troubles.
快! 快! 快开车!
Go! Go! Go!
求你了 帝博格 帝博格 停一下
Please.T-bag. T-bag,please.
我需要这笔钱
I need that money.
该死 你个狗娘养的
Andale, you son of a bitch.
求你了 帝博格 我求你了
Please, T-bag, I'm begging you.
请停下 停下! 不!
No
船几时开?
What time does the ship leave?
十分钟后
About ten minutes.
真不敢相信我们又要逃亡了
I can't believe we're running again.
现在跟以前不同
It's different now,man.
-是么?    -是的
-You think so?  -Yeah.
我们把那婊子搞垮了
We brought the bitch down.
是她自己辞职的 林肯
She stepped down,Linc.
那也是因为我们啊
Because of us.
但你还是个在逃的谋杀犯啊
Yet you're still wanted for murder.
当你来福克斯河时...
When you came to Fox River...
还记得你说了什么吗?
remember what you said?
你说 "我会把你弄出去的"
You said, "I'm gonna break you out of here.
我现在好好的 你做到了
I'm alive. You did that.
看看好的方面吧
You want to look for the good you look there.
来吧  让我们有始有终
Come on, let's just finish what you started.
莱娜斯今天让整个国家和全世界感到震惊
Reynolds shocked the country and the world today
由于某种癌症
when she unexpectedly resigned
她突然辞去了总统职位
'cause of somekind cancer
与此同时 新闻报道说...
We'll be bringing you more information as the...
喂?
Hello?
嘿 你还好么?
Hey, are you all right?
是的 我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
我刚听说了总统的事
I just heard about the president.
到底怎么回事?
What, what does it mean?
说明我们得马上离开了
It means it's time to go.
那好... 什么时候?
Okay... when?
十分钟后
Ten minutes.
你还要多久?
How far away are you?
5分钟 听着 莎拉
Five.Listen, Sara,
林肯和我在船上
Linc and I are on the ship.
只能这样了
This is it.
我们不会再回来 所以 呃...
There's no turning back now, so, uh...
我知道这不是你想要的生活
I know it's not what you wanted from your life,
不过要是你有兴趣的话 这里还有个位置
but in case your interested,there is room for one more.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield,
你在邀请我一起去远航看日出么?
you asking me to sail off into the sunset with you?
呃 其实是艘货船 不过 呃... 算是吧
Well, it's more of a freighter, but, uh... yes.
我会到的
I'll be there.
一会儿见
I'll see you soon.
她正朝兰德威尔去
She's heading west on Leadwell.
好的
All right.
盯着她 我马上到
Stay on her, I'll be right there.
这他妈算什么啊?
What the hell's this?
我尽力了
I tried, boss.
你看到他逃掉的
You saw how he just took off.
我只看到一个逃出来的蠢蛋
The only thing I'm seeing is an escaped con,
摇尾乞怜像只狗一样
who's begging to be taken nort-ay.
好吧
Okay,
好吧 听着 或许我们可以打电话给出租车公司
Okay, look, maybe we could call the cab company
问下帝博格去哪了
and find out where T-bag was dropped off.
这还像句人话
Now, you're talking.
我看到电话了...
I saw some phone...
要怎么样你才肯放过我们?
what's it going to take for you to forget you ever found us?
没钱商量个屁啊
There ain't enough pesos in TJ.
你确定?
You sure about that?
来吧 尽管开枪吧
Go ahead, shoot.
不过这办法好像不太好吧
But it might not be the best idea seeing as
只有我一个人知道你那小甜心被关在哪
how I'm the only one who knows where your chiquita's tied up.
玛丽克鲁兹到底在哪?
Where is Maricruz?
要是我告诉你 那我不是死定了
If I tell you, I'm as good as dead.
当然了 要是你开枪 那她也死定了
Of course if you shoot, so is she.
-你在胡扯        -像是么?
-You're bluffing me. -Am I?
我跟你直说吧
Let me tell you in words
让你更清楚点
you might be more familiar with.
她在一个洞里
She's in "the hole"
有足够的水和食物可以维持三个星期
with enough food and water to last about three weeks
要是再久一点的话
Any longer than that
你的小甜心就成人肉干了
your sweet little plum's gonna dry up like a raisin.
-要是她有事的话 告诉我...           -告诉你?
If anything happens to her,so help me...  -help you?
照我说是该你帮我吧
Way I see it,it's you who's gotta help me.
我得不到钱的话
'Cause you ain't gettin' your hands
你就休想得到你的甜心
on that girl 'til I get my hands on that money.
我想我们可以成为拍档了吧
Guess that makes us partners.
要走了
Here we go.
她还没到
She's not here.
莎拉
Sara,
怎么了?
what's the matter?
船就要开了
The ship is leaving.
-迈克尔...   -出什么事了?
-Michael...  -what's wrong?
莎拉
Sara
我已经上船了
I'm already on board.
对不起 我想刚才一定是没看到你
I'm sorry, I must have just missed you.
-你在哪?        -我们在甲板上
-Where are you? -We're on deck.
好的
Great.
我就上来
I'm on my way up.
爱你
Love you.
没事吧?
We good?
清理出口...
Clear vehicles platform 9!
是的
Yeah.
该死的
Son of a bitch.
-他在哪?       -我不知道
-Where is he?  -I don't know.
别再耍把戏了 莎拉
No more games, Sara.
你正赶去见他呢
You were on your way to see him.
不 不是的
No, I wasn't.
你刚才这是强制逃脱联邦探员的监护
You were just compelled to flee the custody of a federal agent?
我找不到她
I couldn't find her.
莎拉...
Sara...
我们得回去
we got to go back.
迈克尔 不行的 你什么都做不了
Michael, you can't, there's nothing you can do.
总会有办法的
There's always something you can do.
这次不行
Not this time.
真的不行
Not this time, man.
都已结束了
It's done.
对不起
I'm sorry.
给我斯科菲尔德还是进监狱  你自己选？
Scofield or prison.
我只是想要个油炸圈饼
I just wanted a donut, sir.
给她油炸圈饼
Get her a donut.
给她个油炸圈饼 行么? 给她油炸圈饼
Can we get her a donut? Get her a donut.
给她一打的油炸圈饼!
Get her a dozen donuts!
拷起来!
Look her up!
你他妈到底去哪了  迈克尔?
Where the hell did you go, Michael?
马宏现在怎么样了?
So,where the hell is Mahone?
我不知道  长官
I don't know, sir.
他已经失踪一个多星期了
He's been MIA for the last week or so.
你认为他知道我们在调查他了吗
You think he knows I've been barking up one of his trees.
下午好  弗兰克林先生
Mr. Franklin, good afternoon.
这位是里查德.萨林斯
This is Richard Sullins.
美国联帮调查局内务部主管
Director of Internal Affairs at the FBI.
我的工作是
Which means
当我们的人犯错时
whenever one of our people does something wrong,
我就有责任把他们纠正过来
it's my job to make it right.
我们到底要谈些什么?
How right are we talking about?
当然  让我说的明白些
Well, let's be clear,
你是个重罪罪犯
you are a convicted felon
一个从州政府监狱逃出来的人
who broke out of a state penitentiary,
我能做的非常有限
there's only so much I can do.
好啊  那我也没什么好说的
Well, there's only so much I can say.
现在  我很抱歉
Now, I'm sorry
我不相信任何人
if I seem a little bit skeptical.
上次有个联邦探员
But the last time a federal agent came up
来跟我做交易
in here offering me a deal,
居然还附上一根绳子...
there was a string attached...
让我上吊自杀
that I was supposed to put around my neck.
我被批准给你...嗯...给你减刑
I've been authorized to, uh,offer you a reduced sentence
作为交换  你得指证马宏
in exchange for your testimony against agent Mahone,
你18年的刑期将被缩短到只有18个月
instead of 18 years,you'll be looking at 18 months.
18个月?
18 months?
嘿  你知道吗
Hey, you know what?
那家伙想要杀死我
That man tried to kill me.
如果被他发现我还活得如此滋润
So as soon as he finds out that I'm singing,
我可能连十八天都活不到
I probably won't even last 18 days.
富兰克林先生...
Mr. Franklin...
他威胁我的家庭
he threatened my family.
我现在要离开这里去保护他们
Now, I need to be out there protecting them.
所以  除非你能给我这些
So until you can offer me something like that...
否则我不会为这该死的事作证的
I'm not testifying to a damn thing.
警卫!
Guard!
我给你自由
Free man.
你和你的家庭
You and your family.
将得到证人保护  一个全新开始
Witness protection, fresh start.
档案记录也清除么?
Clean record?
完全清除
Spick-and-span.
我要书面记录和一个见证人
You put that in writing and you got yourself a witness.
长官?
Sir?
我敲了门  但是...
I knocked, but...
你还好么?
you okay?
你觉得这个看起来象什么?
What does that look like to you?
这儿  就在这儿
There, right there.
恩  一个三角形?
Uh, it's a triangle.
对  我也这么认为
Yeah,I thought so,too.
那这个呢?  在这儿
How about this? Right there.
一个数学符号--∏
It's the mathematical symbol for pi.
3.14
我想这是个日期  或者地区代码
I'm thinking date, area code.
314  那是密苏里
314, that's Missouri.
那你认为斯科菲尔德在那儿?
So you think Scofield's there?
我怀疑是
I doubt it.
你的希腊字母表呢 兰探员?
How's your greek alphabet, agent Lang?
我不知道  我想大概...
I don't know. I guess it's...
如果我说三角形就是三角洲
what if I told you that triangle was a delta
而这个
and that this,
这里不是数学符号∏而是一个字母呢
this here was not the symbol pi but the letter?
我从没在他的纹身的图片中看到过这些
I didn't see any of those in the photos of the tattoos.
不是纹身里的
They weren't in the tattoos.
我们把这些从硬盘中找出
We pulled these from his original sketches
放到他的初稿里
off the hard drive.
斯科菲尔德将他所有逃跑的步骤都标明了
Scofield numbered all of the steps of his escape.
这就是他怎样将所有的都制订好计划
It's how he kept everything in order,
但看上去却没有使用数字
but it looks like that he didn't use numbers,
因为他用了这些字母  就像  恩...
that he used letters like, um...
纹身的草图
a sketch of this tattoo.
艾伦.施怀特标注了一个
Allan Schweitzer marked with an Alpha,
希腊字母表的第一个字母
first letter of the greek alphabet.
Fiephis 计划
First step of his plan.
腊字母表的第五个字母
Epsilon, fifth letter of the greek alphabet.
计划的第五步
Fifth step in his plan.
这是
Here's theta,
还有
and kappa...
那些呢?
how about that?
边境  对吧?
Tau? At the border, right?
现在接近尾声了  想和我一起去么?
Getting closer to the end now, you with me?
所以你认为...
So you think...
他的
his omega...
希腊字母表的最后一个字母
the last letter of the greek alphabet.
就是他的计划的最后一步
Is the last step of his plan.
那是什么?
What is that?
-花中的基督?  -一朵玫瑰
-Christ in a flower?   -A rose.
还有这些数字-- 617.
And these numbers... 617.
也许是圣经的第6章第17节
Could be biblical; chapter 6, verse 17.
6-1-7  617
6-1-7, 617.
六月十七号
June 17th.
哦  今天几号?
Oh, what's today?
十五号
The 15th.
所以无论他的最后一步是什么...
So whatever his last step is...
都有可能是在这两天
it's going to happen in two days.
不
No.
没有找到斯塔姆先生这名字
There is Mr. Stammel in our system.
你去租车的那地方查查
You should check with the buses and the car rental...
-他说什么?         -没什么  没有发现
What's he saying?  -Nothing. The same as the rest.
也许他没搞明白
Maybe he don't comprehend.
西班牙人总认识这个吧?
What's spanish for "ins"?
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
我们在墨西哥
We're in Mexico.
你在这儿不能乱来的
You're the illegal one here.
嘿  他可能在美国有家人
Hey, it doesn't mean he ain't got family up north
正试图想要拿到绿卡呢
trying to clean their way to a green card.
他懂我的意思
He knows what I'm talking about.
我讨厌这个美国佬  但我需要他帮我
我女友和我女儿遇上了麻烦
我们要找的人
是唯一可以救他们的人
他用一个叫埃 斯塔姆的名字
如果你有消息的话 请...
...打这个电话
我会非常感激的
哦  你对我真好  苏珊宝贝
oh, you are too good to me, Suzi-Q.
知道我喜欢这个
Mm. Just how I like it.
我怎会如此幸运?
How did I get so lucky?
哦  不  泰迪熊
Oh, no, Teddy bear.
我才是幸运的那个
I'm the lucky one.
我遇见你的那天...
The day I met you...
是我重生的时刻
was the day I was born.
我们到时间了
Mm. We're out of time.
不  苏珊  我们要一辈子在一起
No, Susan, we got our whole lives together.
不  我的意思是  一小时到了
No, I mean, the hour is up.
我会非常用心的照顾你的  好吗?
I'll take care of you plenty, okay?
我们都这么熟了
And since we're rolling here,
所以让我们  你知道  回到...
so let's, you know, get back...
怎么说呢-- 烹饪或者美容  怎么样?
how's it... what's cookin', good lookin'?
如果你先付我些钱  我会感觉好点
I would really feel better if you paid me up front.
那我先告诉你 如果你乖乖听话
And I told you up front that if you did this right,
我会给你好处的的  所以呢...
I would take care of you, so...
你只付了我一小时的钱
you paid me for an hour.
现在时间到了
The hour is up.
如果你想让我留下来  就得多付些钱给我
If you want me to stay, I need more money.
很好  很好  气氛都被你破坏了
Great, great, you ruined it.
不必了
Thanks.
知道吗  刚才有那么会儿 我还挺喜欢
You know, for a second there,I was actually like,
这个有情有义的妞
this chick has a brain in her head.
你要真如此 就不可能在街上卖了 是吧?
Then, if you did, you wouldn't be a street whore, right?
告诉你
You know,
我压根就不知道这个叫苏西宝贝的贱人是谁
I don't know who this Suzi-Q bitch is,
不过 怪不得她要跟你脱离关系了
but no wonder she wants nothing to do with you.
你刚才称她为贱人  是吧
You didn't just call her a bitch, did you?
好
Okay.
我数到三
I am going to count to three,
要是你还不放开手
and if you don't put your arm down,
我就要喊了
I'm going to scream.
一  二...
One, T...
我们成功了
we made it.
还没呢
Not yet.
我们得先去见个人
First there's someone we need to see.
有人想到什么了吗
Okay, who's got what?
玫瑰中的耶稣
Christ as a rose
是贯穿圣经各章的共同主题
is a pretty common theme that runs through the bible.
马丁路德曾经在自己的族徽里面引用过
Martin Luther adopted it as his coat of arms.
教徒们深信耶稣曾经死而复生
And there's the belief that Christ rose from the dead.
这就是斯科菲尔德的最后一步棋 获得新生
This is Scofield's final step, a new life.
新生 这里面可能有文章
Life. Could be something there.
没错 你...
You...
把这些记下来
keep track of this on the board.
记在板上
On the board.
-惠勒在哪儿?      -找到了
-Where's Wheeler? -Here we go.
哈莫尼人
The Harmonists
印第安纳州新哈莫尼地区的第一批定居者
first settlers of New Harmony,Indiana
曾用一朵金色的玫瑰作为耶稣的象征
used a golden rose as their symbol for Christ.
有这种可能
That's a reach.
有种花就叫做耶稣玫瑰
There's a flower called the Christmas Rose.
难道耶稣玫瑰指的不是那个德国代码吗?
Wasn't "Christ Rose" a German code name for, uh,
那次直接导致帝国反击战的纳粹战役?
the counterattack by the nazis that led to the battle of the Bulge?
在哪儿发生的?
Where was that?
阿德雷丝森林 在比利时和德国边境的交界处
Ardennes forest on the Belgium-Germany border.
就是那儿
Yeah,
的确是个理想的藏身之所
not a bad place to hide
如果他们找得到的话
if they can find it.
你再查查看?
So you gonna look into that?
对 没错 还有什么?
Yeah. All right, what else?
耶稣是在复活节那天死而复生的
Christ actually rose from the dead on Easter.
复活节日...
Easter Sunday...
谁有斯科菲尔德的资料?
who's got Scofield's file?
在我这儿 给你
Um, here we go.
这儿
Here.
玫瑰里的耶稣
Christ in a rose.
这是什么意思?
Yeah, what about it?
斯科菲尔德母亲的名字
Scofield's mother's name.
克里斯蒂娜.罗斯.斯科菲尔德
Christina Rose Scofield.
但我以为她过世了
Hmm, but I thought she was dead.
恩 我也这样以为
Well, so did I.
他们逃出福克斯河监狱后
The very first thing that Scofield did
斯科菲尔德做的第一件事就是
when they broke out of Fox River is he picked up
去墓地取回他事先藏好的物品
a bunch of supplies that he had stashed in a grave.
我要你们去弄清楚斯科菲尔德的妈妈埋在哪儿
I want you to find out where Scofield's mother's buried.
然后呢?
And what?
看看她是不是被埋在那儿
And see if she's buried.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
-巴拿马是怎么回事?   -什么巴拿马?
-What about Panama?  -What about Panama?
我们检查他的硬盘时
Well, when we found his hard drive,
里面有很多信息是关于美国中部的
it was full of information about central America,
尤其是巴拿马
Panama in particular.
他肯定猜到了
Which he knows you have.
这小子太狂妄自大了
The guy's got all kinds of hubris,
但以他的智商 既然猜到你会在那儿等他
but he's smart enough to stay out of a country
他肯定会远离那个国家
where he knows you'll be waiting for him.
除非那儿有他需要的东西
Unless there's something there that he needs.
或者人
or someone.
我要一张巴拿马地图
I want a map of Panama,
找出斯科菲尔德的妈妈 克里斯蒂娜.罗斯
and find out if Scofield's mom,Christina Rose,
是不是在中美洲有家人
has any family in central America,
或者财产
any property,
任何东西
anything.
上次我坐公车 就像这样
The last time I was on a bus like this,
不过是去福克斯河监狱的
I was heading to Fox River.
这个国家太棒了
This country's amazing.
非常美
It's beautiful.
这是什么味道 伙计?
What's that smell, man?
香蕉
Bananas.
还有甘蔗
And sugar cane.
是巴拿马出口最多的商品
That's Panama's biggest exports.
拜托
Come on.
自从我们脱险后 你一直在说巴拿马和坐公车会很颠簸
You've been talking about Panama and bumpy bus rides ever since we broke out,
现在我们已经上路了...
and now that we're actually doing it...
她本应该和我们一起的
she should have been here with us.
我们已经尽力了
We got all the time in the world for that.
总有一天 你和莎拉...
Some ways down the track, you and Sara...
我们安安静静地坐车 好吗?
can we just get there, please?
当然
Sure.
至今为止 在斯科菲尔德的妈妈和巴拿马之间
So far, no hits on any connection between
还没有找到任何联系
Scofield's mother and Panama.
但有38条与克里斯蒂娜.罗斯有关的信息
But there are 38 listings of Christina Rose
各种各样的姓氏和名字的组合
in various combinations of first name,middle name and last name.
好吧 交叉检索姓名和数字617
All right, cross-reference the names with the numbers 6-1-7
纹身上的那个数字 也许他不代表日期
from the tattoo,Maybe it's not a date.
试试看 它会不会是地址 信箱号什么的
See if it's an address, P.O. Box.
好
Got it.
只要有线索 就打电话给使馆
If anybody pops, call the embassy,
让他们派人抓来那个女人问话
have them send an officer to pick up the woman for questioning.
我想如没有任何确切证据的话...
Um, I don't think we can just
-我们无权逮捕外国居民... -爱国法 兰探员
-arrest a foreign citizen without any...  -Patriot Act, agent Lang.
我随时可以逮捕你奶奶
I could arrest your grandmother
即使以丢失绣花针为由 只要我愿意
for missing a stitch in her macram,if I wanted to.
只要有人在帮斯科菲尔德
If anybody's helping Scofield,
无论是死人还是活人 我都要知道是谁
dead or alive,I want to know who they are.
那个女人?
That her?
对
Yeah.
您好 瓦斯克斯太太
Hola, Mrs. Vasquez.
你来晚了
You're late.
比你事先说的日期晚了很多
It's much later than the date you said.
我们遇到点小麻烦
Well, we ran into a little bit of trouble.
这是谁?
Who is this?
一个商业伙伴
It's a business associate.
克里斯蒂娜.罗斯
Christina Rose.
我记得
I remember.
你可以去这儿找
You will find her here.
祝你好运
Buena suerte.
谢谢
Gracias.
呃...
Oh, um...
在外面等我
I'll meet you outside.
我忘了问句话
I forgot to ask something.
好
All right.
我能用下电话吗?
Do you have a phone I could use?
您好 请帮我接国际长途
Yes, uh, I need an international operator, please.
美国
United States.
号码312-346...
It's, uh, 312-346...
-你在干吗?  -打电话
-what the hell are you doing?   -Making a phone call.
不行
You can't.
我们连她是死是活都不知道 林肯
We don't even know if she's alive or dead, Linc.
如果莎拉被抓的话
If Sara's in custody,
她的电话就在别人手里
they got her phone.
你想被抓吗?
You want to get caught?
喂
Yeah.
我最讨厌三种事 阿历克斯
Three things I hate, Alex.
堵车 曲棍球...
Traffic, hockey...
还有不停地为同一件事给你打电话
and calling you with the same question over and over.
那就别再打给我了 不过我确信
Well, then don't call me anymore,but I do believe
兄弟两个现在在巴拿马
the brothers are in Panama.
是吗?
Is that so?
具体在哪得从斯科菲尔德的纹身上找答案
The key to exactly where is on one of Scofield's tattoos.
你把目标缩小到一个国家 我喜出望外啊
While I'm thrilled you've narrowed it down to a country,
但这不是我想说的事
that's not why we're talking.
本杰明.富兰克林还活着...
Benjamin Miles Franklin is alive...
我知道
I'm aware of that, yeah...
...而且免除监禁
and being released from custody.
这不可能
That's not possible.
得我这边批准才行
They would need permission from my office.
很高兴知道这事儿由你负责
Good to know you're on top of things.
给我把惠勒探长找来
Find me agent Wheeler.
他现在可以见你
He'll see you now.
很抱歉我这样问 但是 先生...
Forgive me for asking, sir, but...
难道我们就不能在我办公室谈吗?
couldn't we be doing this in my office?
那儿可要舒服多了
It'd be much more comfortable.
我想我们得找个更安全的地方
I felt we needed to speak freely.
接下来的这段时间 就是情报界所谓的盲点
the next several hours this is what those intelligence
ageney comunity refer to as a "blind spot".
有人告诉我 这跟太阳的位置有关
Something to do with the position of the sun, I'm told.
可以干扰长途录音设备
Disrupts long-distance recording devices.
我很抱歉 关于...
If I may apologize again, sir, for...
总统的事 实在很不幸
the unfortunate outcome with the president.
我知道她对于我们来说很重要 我保证
I know how important she was to our interests,and I assure you
-接下来 我会...         -你接下来
-that moving forward, I'll...  -you won't be
不用做任何事 直到你先把这事解释清楚
moving anywhere until you can explain to me how this happened.
那兄弟俩儿... 他们成功了...
The brothers... they're making it...
他们还活着
still alive.
还活着
Yes.
是的 他们逃到国外
It appears they were able to flee the country.
哪里?
To where?
马宏认为他们在巴拿马
Mr. Mahone seems to believe they're in Panama.
马宏知道他们在巴拿马的具体位置么？
Does our Mr. Mahone know where exactly in Panama they are?
不知道  怎么了?
Not yet. Why?
你对索纳知道多少  金先生?
How much do you know about Sona, Mr. Kim?
并不太了解
Only what I've been given clearance on.
我们现在的处境
Perhaps what our situation requires...
要求我们改变策略
is a change in strategy.
还要多久法院才会
How long until the court
批准对马宏的逮捕令?
approves the arrest warrant for Mahone?
就快了
Should be anytime now.
我们在等起诉书
We're just waiting for the indictment to come down.
我有问题要问你
Okay, well, I've got a question for you.
要是他在这怎么办? 我不能一直躲着
What if he's in there? I can't keep avoiding him.
他很会察言观色 他是干这个的
He reads people. That's what he does.
万一他知道了我有参与这事
And if he finds out that I'm involved in this,
我需要人保护...
I'm gonna need some protection from...
惠勒  冷静  深呼吸
Wheeler, relax. Take a breath.
马宏只能知道你写给他的东西
The only thing Mahone can read is what you write for him.
你只要做到
Can you act normal?
表现得跟平常一样就可以了  我们绝不能让他逃了
That's all you have to do... the last thing we
want is for him to get spooked and take off.
这一切就要结束了
This is all gonna be over soon.
好的 谢谢
All right. Thank you.
不  该谢谢你
No. Thank you.
惠勒  你去哪了?
Wheeler. Where you been?
我必须这样做
I got to do this.
你干什么  阿历克斯?
What are you doing, Alex?
我没有装监听装置
I'm not wearing a wire.
你告诉我
You gonna tell me
是怎么回事?
what's going on here?
以前 在英国...
In old England...
对背叛的惩罚是
the punishment for a traitorous act
砍头
was beheading.
行刑的时候
Following the execution,
他们会揪住你的头发 使你的头抬起来
they would hold up the severed head by the hair...
并不像一般人以为的那样 是为了让围观的人看你
not as most people think,for the crowd to see the head,
而是为了让你看着下面的人
but for the head to see the crowd,
因为砍掉脑袋之后 你还能有8秒钟的意识
because consciousness sticks around for another eight seconds.
这样是为了让叛徒
The idea was that it would give the traitor
最后看一眼...
one more chance to take a look at...
你不会这么做  是吧?
you don't want to do this, okay?
你耐心点...
Just take a moment...
如果你要在背后刺我一刀
If you're gonna stab me in the back,
惠勒探员  得注意
agent Wheeler, be smart enough
先把刀藏好
to cover up the knife.
你这个星期去见了
You go and visit Franklin
富兰克林3次
three times this week,
一天两次打电话给萨林斯?
called Sullins, what, twice a day?
跟我这么久 你都学到什么了?
Didn't you learn anything working for me?
干什么都要不留痕迹  除非...
You got to cover your tracks, unless you...
除非你想被抓
unless you want to get caught.
你想让我知道是你
You wanted me to know it was you.
你是凶手 阿历克斯
You're a killer, Alex.
是吗
Is that so?
从你的花园提取的土壤样本
Soil samples taken from your yard
显示和奥斯卡 夏尔斯的失踪有关
in connection with the disappearance of Oscar Shales.
对大卫·阿克斯的死
Forensics is prepared to submit a report detailing
法庭准备就弹痕的不规则性
the irregularities in the shooting of
提交一份详细的报告
David "Tweener" Apolskis.
你无视双方约定
There's your blatant disregard for protocol
对阿布鲁奇的死负有责任...
in the death of John Abruzzi...
那个越狱犯说我让他自杀
and the escaped con who says that I told him to kill himself.
你以为他的证词
You think his testimony is gonna
能让你如愿以偿
send you into the promised land.
你可以除掉我
You can erase me, too.
但是除不掉事实
But it's not gonna erase the very real fact that
那就是 你等在监狱度过余生吧
you're gonna spend the rest of your life in prison.
你知道...
You know...
你让我想起我还是个年轻探员的时候
you remind me of myself when I was a young agent.
什么
What?
我希望这是对我的赞扬
I wish I could take that as a compliment.
你干得不错 惠勒
That's some real fine work, Wheeler.
干得好
Good job.
不要让别人吓唬到你...
Don't you let anyone scare you...
从而去做错事
into doing the wrong thing.
我带你进去
Let me take you in.
不管你遇到什么麻烦 我们都能解决
Whatever mess you're in, we can clean it up.
只有一个办法  可以解决这问题
There's only one way to clean this...
唯一的办法
one way.
有访客
Hey. Got a visitor.
谁
Yeah, who?
不认识
I don't know.
我只管把你带下去
I was just instructed to bring you down.
嘿 听着 我哪儿也不去
Hey, look, I ain't going nowhere until
除非你告诉我是谁要见我
you tell me who it is I'm meeting, all right?
给我放手
You got to stop it.
听我一句 行么
Listen to me for a second, all right?
你们先去看看是谁
That's all you got to do is go out there and check.
是不是一个长的有点高的
Guy's kind of tall, okay?
你们绝不能这么做
It's the least that you can do.
什么
What?
爸爸
Daddy!
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
过来
Come here.
爸爸非常爱你
Oh. Oh, daddy loves you so much.
所以 嗯...这是真的吧
So, um... is it real?
他说你会被释放
He says you're gonna go free,
我们再也不必躲躲藏藏了
that we don't have to run anymore.
我说 怎么了
I mean, what happened?
怎么回事? 嘿 嘿 嘿
What changed?
别担心了
Don't you worry about it.
你只需知道我已经把事情解决了
You just know that your man handles things.
难道不是那样吗
Ain't that right?
没错
That's right.
好了
Okay.
难以置信
I don't believe it,
不过没关系
But okay.
本杰明
Benjamin,
我可以和你聊几句吗
if I could just have a quick word.
噢...
Uh... .
是的 嘿
yeah
到大厅里去等我下
Why don't you go down the hall for just a quick second.
可以吗 我马上就过去
Okay? I'll be right there.
好的
Okay
这是
Here it is.
新的地址
New address,
新的身份
new identities.
现在  检察官正准备找你
Now, the prosecutor's gonna be getting in touch with you
记录你的证词  所以你只需
to go over your testimony,so you
确保按照他所说的
just make sure you show up
准时露下面就行了
where he says and when he says.
好 行 行
Yeah, okay, okay.
我现在自由了  对吗?
But I'm a free man, right?
自由了
Free man.
等下 马宏会怎样
Wait a minute. What about Mahone,
你知道 因为我不想在下半辈子里
you know 'cause I don't want to
老是提心吊胆的 你明白吗
be looking over my shoulder for the rest of my life, you feel me?
马宏的事我会处理
You let me worry about Mahone.
你不要添乱就行了
You just worry about staying out of trouble.
不会有问题的 相信我
You ain't gonna have a problem with that,trust me.
别搞砸了
Don't screw it up.
还有多远
How much further?
不远了
Not far.
你知道 不论怎么
You know, for what it's worth,
你知道 我想
You know,
没有人强迫莎拉做她所做的
no one forced Sara to do what she did.
你怎么做到心安理得
Whatever gets you through the night.
你到底什么意思
The hell does that mean?
我没有让你利用她
I didn't ask you to use her.
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
你为何如此 兄弟
Whatever gets you through the night, buddy.
你知道是什么让我惊讶吗 林肯?
You know what amazes me, Linc?
你不关心任何事
Nothing ever registers with you.
从来不
Ever.
你把正义抛到脑后去了 不是吗?
Just rolls right off your back, doesn't it?
我们毁了莎拉的生活 可是你并不在意
We ruined Sara's life and it's like you don't even care.
-那你打算如何?         -我们在这里
-That what you think?  -Well, we're here,
可莎拉回到监狱里去了
and Sara's back there in prison.
-你认为公平么?   -世界本来就不公平
-Does that seem fair to you?  -None of it's fair.
你可别把这跟你失去女友扯到一起
Just don't make this about boy loses girl.
那这算什么 林肯?
Who should it be about, Linc?
韦斯特莫兰德? 大卫?
Westmoreland? Tweener?
-LJ? LJ的妈妈? -你给我住口
-LJ? LJ's mom? -Let me stop you right there.
记得那个被杀的警卫吗
Remember the name of the guard that was murdered
-死于我引起的骚乱的那个?        -闭嘴 迈克尔
-because of the riot I started? -Shut up, Michael.
-还记得他的名字吗         -闭嘴
Do you even remember his name?  -Shut up
那我敢说你一定记得维罗尼卡的名字吧 不是吗
I bet you remember Veronica's name though,don't you?
你敢再提一次 我发誓...
You mention her name again, I swear to god...
还有帝博格!
What about T-bag?
林肯 他现在逃出来了 只因为我们
Linc, he's out there, now, because of us!
你和我
You and me!
他夺走的每一条生命
Every life he takes,
我们手上都沾着血
that's blood on our hands.
为了什么啊
And for what?
不是我让你去做的
I didn't ask you to do what you did.
他们会杀了你的 林肯
They were gonna kill you, Linc!
是啊 你应该让他们杀了我
Well, maybe you should've let them!
你居然这么说
Take that back.
莎拉的状况再怎么糟糕
As bad as I feel about Sara,
至少她还有的选择
she had a choice.
但维罗尼卡没有
Veronica didn't.
我听着她死去 迈克尔
I listened to her die, Michael.
我听着她死去 可是
I listened to her die, and there was...
可是我什么也做不了
there was nothing I could do.
什么也做不了
Nothing.
我们失去的太多了 兄弟
We've lost so much, man.
我们不能再承受失去彼此
We can't afford to lose each other.
我们不能
We just can't.
要出门么 阿历克斯
You going somewhere, Alex?
不知道 你说呢
I don't know. Am I?
来吧
Come on.
你知道我不喜欢把手弄脏
You know I don't like to get my hands dirty.
这很让人惊讶吧 用恰当的方式刺激一个人
It's surprising the things a man
可以让他为你做任何事
will do when properly motivated.
这都是你让我做的
Wasn't it you who told me that?
你知道 我会立刻杀了你 如果我觉得
You know, I would kill you right now if I thought
那会让我获得哪怕一丁点儿平静
it would give me an ounce of peace.
那你怎么才能平静
And what would give you peace?
我撑到了现在
I've been able to hold it together
经历了这么多
through all this...
只因黑暗尽头的那一点希望
because there was a light at the end of the tunnel.
生命...
Life...
在黑暗的那一头
at the end of the tunnel,
为我 为我的家人
for me, for my family.
可是现在
And now what?
我儿子
Do you see my son?
我妻子 这些你都看到了么?
Do you see my wife?
我得到了什么
What have I got?
你给了我什么
What have you given me?
如果我告诉你
What if I was to tell you
还有办法
that there was something that could turn that light...
带回你的希望
back on?
你会如何?
What would you say?
你之前也是这么承诺的
I'd say that's the same offer you made
当你把我拽进来的时候 你个小杂种
when you dragged me into this,you little bastard.
现在你看看 我得到什么了
And look what it's got me now.
他们会把我拉到公众面前
They're gonna drag me before the public.
他们会起诉我 像个...
They've gonna prosecute me like-like...
像个杀人犯
like some kind of murderer.
还有 还有...证据
There's-there's... there's evidence.
非常有效的
Really hard,
确凿的证据 没办法摆脱的
tangible evidence,that you can't take away.
对的
You're right...
但是我可以帮你摆脱
but I can help you get away.
况且现在
And at this point,
我觉得你也别无其他选择
I don't think you've got any other options.
西奥多·巴格威尔已经在墨西哥被发现了
Theodore "T-bag" Bagwell was apprehended in Mexico.
哦 我猜 你想要他死
Oh, let me guess.You want him dead.
噢 不
Oh, no.
我们有
There's been a,uh,
一个策略上的改变
change in strategy.
我们需要他活着
We're gonna need him alive.
我们在谈论一个真正的
I'm talking about a very real
完美结局 阿历克斯
finish line here, Alex.
你都已走到这一步了
You've come so far.
我还得再走多远?
How much further would I have to go?
哦 你很幸运
Well, you're lucky.
你只需再去趟巴拿马
For this, you only have to go to Panama.
我已经不太想的起来
I'm trying to remember the last time
我们以前正常的生活是什么样子了
our lives made any kind of sense.
在妈妈去世前
Before mom died.
我们3个在一起的时候
When it was just the three of us.
她就在那儿了
Well, there she is.
你好 兰
Hello, Lang.
你怎么了 我是说
What's going on? I mean,
你办公室里有好多人进进出出
there's all kinds of suits over here going through your office.
我晚点给你解释
I'll explain later.
好吧
All right.
你收到传真了吗
Um... did you get the fax?
没有 怎么了
No. Why?
什么内容
What do you got?
一些克利斯蒂娜 罗斯的消息
Some information on Christina Rose
你可能感兴趣
you might find interesting.
斯科菲尔德抢劫银行4个月前
Looks like she was commissioned about four months
巴拿马一个建筑商安帕洛 瓦斯克
before Scofield robbed that bank by a builder
就把她租用了
in Panama named Amparo Vasquez.
婊子养的
Son of a bitch.
它很漂亮
She's beautiful.
是啊  它并不是真的远航船 不过...
Yeah, she's not the real thing, but...
去哪儿啊 兄弟
so where to, man?
想去哪儿都行
Anywhere we want.
这一切真的结束了
So, it really over?
对 宝贝 结束了
Yeah, baby, it's really over.
好的
Okay.
怎么了 宝贝
What is it, baby?
哦 没什么
huh,nothing.
我们回家
Let's go home.
我们去查过了玛琳纳克的火车站
Okay, so we checked the train station in Malinalco,
皮布拉的汽车站
the-the bus depot in Puebla,
还有所有的旅馆
and just about every hotel there is.
喂
Hello.
嘿 说慢点 桑科
Hey, hey, hey, slow down, Sancho.
等一下
Uno Momento.
找你的
It's for you.
你好
Hola.
就是旅游局的那个人
That was the guy from the tourism Bureau.
-找到他         -在哪?
-He found him.  -Where?
一个叫依.斯坦摩的刚登上了去巴拿马的飞机
An E. Stammel just boarded a plane to Panama city.
他去巴拿马搞什么
What the hell's he doing in Panama?
你会说英语吗
You speak english?
说"早上好 泰迪"
Say, uh, "good morning, Teddy".
早上好 泰迪
Good morning, Teddy.
这么说 你不会说英语
So then, actually, no, you don't speak english.
这儿有人说英语吗
Hablan ingles around here?
说"早上好 泰迪"
Say, "good morning, Teddy.
早上好 泰迪
Good morning, Teddy.
说"早上好 泰迪熊"
Say, "good morning, Teddy bear.
早上好 泰迪熊
Good morning, Teddy bear.
喜欢假发吗
Do you like wigs?
只要给够钱 我什么都喜欢
For the right money, I like anything.
什么都没有
Oh. There's nothing.
网上没有任何关于莎拉被捕的消息
Nothing online about Sara's arrest.
也许他们不想声张
Maybe they're keeping it quiet.
有别的消息吗
What about the message board?
留言板那里
The goldfinch thing?
只有关于西诺的和...
Just something from C-Note and...
有苏克雷的消息了
There is a message from Sucre.
还在逃吗
Still running, huh?
怎么了
What?
苏克雷说帝博格就在这儿 在巴拿马
Sucre says T-bag's here, in Panama.
他怎么知道的
How the hell does he know?
我不知道 上面说
I don't know. It says,
包还在帝博格那
the bag's still has the bag.
他在巴拿马的芬黛 卡米诺酒店
He's in Panama city at the Fin Del Camino hotel.
如果你们在那
If you're there
并想再逮住他的话
and want to help put that bird back in a cage,
尽管通知我 苏克雷
let me know. Sucre.
这个婊子养的来巴拿马做什么
What the hell is that son of a bitch doing in Panama?
我们得去找他
We got to go after him.
算了 伙计 我们不需要那钱
Just let it be, man. We don't need the money.
不关钱的事 林肯
It's not about the money, Linc.
帝博格还在外面
Whatever good we do from here on out,
我们无论如何也不能过的心安理得
it doesn't matter as long as T-bag's out there.
迈克尔 我们好不容易逃出来的
Michael, we made it.
出了那么多乱子  我们应该...
Too much has gone wrong. If we could just...
尽量弥补一下
if we could just make this right.
巴拿马城一个小时就到了
Panama city,is only an hour away.
现在我们知道他在哪了
And now we know where he's staying.
告诉警察就行了
So call the police.
我选巴拿马是有原因的——
There's a reason I chose Panama...
这里没有引渡法
there's no extradition laws.
他们动不了他
They're not going to touch him.
那我们怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
我再想个办法
I'll figure something out.
想办法
Figure it out?
得了吧 伙计 你连撒个尿都要先计划的
You don't take a piss without a plan, man. Come on.
看着我 我做事从不先计划
Look at me...I never think things through
你看看我现在怎么样了
and look where it got me.
-巴拿马和一条漂亮的船 -这是你弄到的
-Yeah, Panama and a boat-load of booze.  -You got me that.
我给自己弄到的是个死刑
I got me a death sentence.
听着 让我们...
Look, let's just...
出海去 好好想想
get out to sea, think things through,
等时机合适了我们再想办法
when the time's right, we make it right.
好吗
Okay?
乘坐巴拿马航空
Trans Panamanian Airlines
271航班前往巴拿马的旅客请注意
Flight 271 to Panama,
头等舱开始登机了
now boarding all first class passengers.
前往巴拿马的旅客开始登机了
Again, we are now boarding for Panama city.
稍后见
See you soon.
家 甜蜜的家
Home sweet home.
我找到酒了 但是没有柠檬
I got the booze, but the limes are shot.
迈克尔
Michael?!
Michael!
迈克尔